Koushik Katta Devops

Hyderabad, Telangana - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Koushik-Katta/a6b19244854199ec

DevOps Administrator with an experience of $3.4~{\rm years}$ working in a challenging agile

environment, looking forward for a position where I can use my knowledge pursuing my domain

interests. I'm more aligned to work for companies where knowledge and intellectual ability takes

the lead which can utilize a performance driven individual efficiently.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Devops Engineer

Infosys limited - Hyderabad, Telangana -

December 2014 to Present

Hyderabad, since December 2014 to till date.

Skill and Abilities:

Atlassian Tools: Jira, Confluence

Configuration Management: Ansible /Chef

CI Tools: Jenkins

Monitoring Tools: Nagios

Cloud: AWS

Containerization: Docker Build Tools: Bamboo\Maven

Log Tools: Splunk

Databases: RDBMS, MYSQL, Oracle Database Programming Languages: Python and Java

Scripting: Power Shell

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux family, Redhat Linux

Middleware: Websphere, Tomcat, Websphere MQ

Responsibilities:
DEVOPS ADMINISTRATOR
INFOSYS LTD.

Atlassian tools Release Management according

Infosys limited -

December 2014 to Present

to project needs.

 \checkmark Review and upgrade of Plugins to meet project requirements and to achieve better performance.

 \checkmark Configuring Automated Mail handlers, Webhooks as POC to test the new demands raised by client.

 $\label{local-com/r/Koushik-Katta/a6b19244854199ec?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN\\$

- ✓ JIRA Project Management/Administration.
- ✓ Confluence Space Management/Administration.
- ✓ Bitbucket Project/Repository Management/Administration (Enterprise/DataCenter)
- ✓ Integration of Webhooks in Bitbucket.
- ✓ Streamlining tools access management with Crowd.
- 2. Administration and Maintenance of Jenkins
- \checkmark Configure and maintain Jenkins slaves as per the requirement.
- ✓ Jenkins release management.
- \checkmark Work closely with Development teams to configure CI/CD Pipelines to automate their build &
- deployment process.
- ✓ Review, Installation/Upgrade and configuration of Jenkins Plugins.
- ✓ Configuring proxy on the environments to enable security
- ✓ Debug build issues
- 3. Administration and Maintenance of Docker registry
- 4. Working with Open-Source Nagios plugins on demand basis to setup ICINGA monitoring for our $\,$

on-premise Servers/Applications.

- 5. Alerting Setup Splunk.
- 6. Monitoring Dashboards setup using kibana.
- 7. Working with product support teams to resolve the product bugs.
- 8. Involve in client meetings and tool performance reviews to ensure stakeholder satisfaction.
- 9. Work closely with Infrastructure Teams to setup/maintain/improve the above mentioned application on large scale.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering

Lovely Professional University

2010 to 2014

Secondary School Certificate in education

Board of Intermediate education - Hyderabad, Telangana

2008 to 2010

Sister Nivedita School - Karimnagar, Telangana

2008

SKILLS

Jira, Ansible, Jenkins, Splunk, Nagios, Docker, Python, AWS, Bamboo, Linux, Git, Chef, Windows, Powershell Scripting

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

 \bullet Ability to learn new technologies and processes rapidly and implement them in the project.

- Highly motivated with very good problem solving and analytical skills Well organized, with excellent in multitasking and prioritizing the work.
- ullet Effective communicator with an ability to convey ideas in speaking and writing.
- Excellent analytical and decision making skills.
- Ability to work in pressurized situation.
- Hard worker and goal oriented.
- Always ready to learn new skills